<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CloudFormation Lab on APN Equip Labs</title>
    <link>http://example.org/cloudformation-lab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CloudFormation Lab on APN Equip Labs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/cloudformation-lab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>1. Exploring the templates</title>
      <link>http://example.org/cloudformation-lab/explore_template/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/cloudformation-lab/explore_template/</guid>
      <description>Please collapse the Source CloudFormation Template file, You can use any text editor to explore the different elements of VPC mentioned in the template. To make it easy for you can copy and paste the entire template into any YAML friendly text editor and collapse / expand the section.
Some Recommendations :
 Notepad++ (https://notepad-plus-plus.org/downloads/) VisualStudioCode. (https://code.visualstudio.com/)  Source CloudFormation Template
Copy this template for the next section.
CLICK HERE</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Create Stack</title>
      <link>http://example.org/cloudformation-lab/create_stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/cloudformation-lab/create_stack/</guid>
      <description>Copy and paste the Sample CloudFormation Template from the previous section to a text file called Sample_VPC_CloudFormation.yml
Log into the AWS Console, and click on CloudFormation and below screen will open:
Now click on Create new stack and browse your initial template to against choose a template option :
Click Next and give stack name. Make sure your stack name should be unique to your account. Leave all other option as default</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Change Your Stack</title>
      <link>http://example.org/cloudformation-lab/change_stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/cloudformation-lab/change_stack/</guid>
      <description>Now that you have explored and deployed your VPC stack, lets modify the template and update the stack to change the environment.
 Go back to the Source Cloudformation template you created before. Modify Section of the Source CloudFormation temoplate, and save the change into a new template file e.g: CloudFormation_Updated.yml.  Solution CloudFormation Template
Click below to look at the Solution CloudFormation template, you can copy and paste this into a new file and update the stack following the next section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. Update Stack</title>
      <link>http://example.org/cloudformation-lab/update_stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/cloudformation-lab/update_stack/</guid>
      <description>Once you modified your existing template , you can use Update Stack option to update your stack. To update select your Stack and click on Actions drop down and you will find Update Stack option.
In Update, Stack screen select browse your updated template. If you have not figured out a solution yet Follow instruction in appendix section to get template
Lab_Solution_CloudFormation_Module_General_ImmersionDay.json.
Now remaining steps are same as you followed in Create stack.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>