<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EC2 Lab (Windows) on APN Equip Labs</title>
    <link>http://example.org/ec2-lab-windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in EC2 Lab (Windows) on APN Equip Labs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/ec2-lab-windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>1. Configure Network</title>
      <link>http://example.org/ec2-lab-windows/configure-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/ec2-lab-windows/configure-network/</guid>
      <description>Before launching a new instance, you will need to configure a new VPC, subnet, internet gateway and routes. All activities should be performed in the us-west-1 region (N. California).
 In AWS console ensure that you are accessing the West-1 region, navigate to VPC.
 In the left navigation pane click &amp;ldquo;Your VPCs&amp;rdquo;
 Click Create VPC then configure:
   Name tag: West VPC
 IPv4 CIDR block: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Configure a Security Group</title>
      <link>http://example.org/ec2-lab-windows/configure-security-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/ec2-lab-windows/configure-security-group/</guid>
      <description>You will now create a security group which will allow remote desktop (RDP) access to an EC2 instance.
A security group acts as a virtual firewall for your instance to control inbound and outbound traffic. When you launch an instance in a VPC, you can assign up to five security groups to the instance. Security groups act at the instance level, not the subnet level. Therefore, each instance in a subnet in your VPC could be assigned to a different set of security groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Configure an IAM User and Policy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/ec2-lab-windows/configure-an-iam-user-and-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/ec2-lab-windows/configure-an-iam-user-and-policy/</guid>
      <description>Next you will work in the Identity and Access Management service (IAM) to create a user and define a custom policy which will restrict EC2 instance launch to a specific (US-West-1) region.
 Navigate to the IAM console
 In the IAM console click Policies on the left
 Click Create Policy
 In the Create Policy page, click the JSON tab.
 Copy the following following text and replace all of the text in the JSON tab:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. Create a Windows EC2 Instance</title>
      <link>http://example.org/ec2-lab-windows/create-windows-ec2-instance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/ec2-lab-windows/create-windows-ec2-instance/</guid>
      <description>You have now created a new user (West_User) and restricted it from creating EC2 instances outside of the us-west-1 region
In this task, you will create a Windows Server 2016 EC2 instance in the us-west-1 (N.California) region. You will perform the following steps as the newly created &amp;ldquo;West_Admin&amp;rdquo; user.
 In a new browser session (Private browsing or from another maching) log in as West_Admin
 Ensure that you are working in the us-west-1 region (N.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5. Validate IAM Policy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/ec2-lab-windows/validate-iam-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/ec2-lab-windows/validate-iam-policy/</guid>
      <description>In this task, you will attempt to create a Windows Server 2016 EC2 instance in the us-east-1 region (N.Virginia). You will perform the following steps as the newly created &amp;ldquo;West_Admin&amp;rdquo; user.
 In a new browser session (Private browsing or from another maching) log in as West_Admin
 Ensure that you are working in the us-east-1 (N.Virginia) region Navigate to EC2 Console and click &amp;ldquo;Launch Instance&amp;rdquo;
 In the search field type: Windows</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6. Cleanup</title>
      <link>http://example.org/ec2-lab-windows/cleanup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/ec2-lab-windows/cleanup/</guid>
      <description>Steps to remove lab content from your AWS account:
 Log back into the console as your primary admin account (not West_Admin)
 From EC2 &amp;ndash; Terminate Windows West Instance
 From VPC &amp;ndash; Delete West VPC
 From IAM &amp;ndash; Delete West_Admin user and EC2_West_Only policy
  Done</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>