<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Golden AMI Assessment Lab on APN Equip Labs</title>
    <link>http://example.org/ami-inspector-lab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Golden AMI Assessment Lab on APN Equip Labs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/ami-inspector-lab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>1. Solutions Overview</title>
      <link>http://example.org/ami-inspector-lab/solutions_overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/ami-inspector-lab/solutions_overview/</guid>
      <description>Here’s how this solution works :
 A scheduled CloudWatch Events event triggers the StartContinuousAssessment AWS Lambda function, which starts the security assessment of your golden AMIs. The StartContinuousAssessment Lambda function performs the following actions:
It reads a JSON parameter stored in the AWS Systems Manager (Systems Manager) Parameter Store. This JSON parameter contains the following metadata for each golden AMI:
 InstanceType – A valid instance-type for launching an EC2 instance of the golden AMI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Tag your Golden AMI</title>
      <link>http://example.org/ami-inspector-lab/tag_golden_ami/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/ami-inspector-lab/tag_golden_ami/</guid>
      <description>To deploy this solution, you must set it up in the AWS Region where you build your golden AMIs. If that AWS Region does not support Amazon Inspector, at the end of your continuous integration pipeline, you can copy your AMIs to an AWS Region where Amazon Inspector assessments are supported.
You can search assessment findings based on golden AMI tags after Amazon Inspector completes an assessment.
To tag a golden AMI by using the AWS Management Console:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Store Golden AMI metadata.</title>
      <link>http://example.org/ami-inspector-lab/store_golden_ami_metadata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/ami-inspector-lab/store_golden_ami_metadata/</guid>
      <description>In this solution we will read the golden AMI metadata from a parameter stored in the Systems Manager Parameter Store. The metadata will be in JSON format and must contain the following information for each golden AMI:
 The Ami-Id is the golden AMI id that we tagged in the previous step ( Hopefully you&amp;rsquo;ve taken note of that, otherwise please review the previous step ). The InstanceType is the EC2 instance type our solution will use to launch the golden AMI with and run the inspection on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. Create Automation Functions</title>
      <link>http://example.org/ami-inspector-lab/create_automation_function/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/ami-inspector-lab/create_automation_function/</guid>
      <description>In this section we will create, create a couple of lambda functions to execute the AMI inspection as well as notify users of the findings
 Creating Lambda Execution Role for StartContinuousAssessmentLambdaFunction
Open your notepad / text editor, create a file named GoldenAMIContinuousAssesment.yml
Reference : https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSCloudFormation/latest/UserGuide/aws-resource-iam-role.html
 Create a resource named StartContinuousAssessmentLambdaRole of type AWS::IAM::Role.
 In the Properties section add ManagedPolicyArns below to allow the lambda function to do basic execution and have access to Amazon Inspector APIs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5. Test Assesment</title>
      <link>http://example.org/ami-inspector-lab/test_assesment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/ami-inspector-lab/test_assesment/</guid>
      <description>Before you schedule vulnerability assessments, you should test the process by running the StartContinuousAssessment function. In this test, you trigger a security assessment and monitor it. You then receive an email after the assessment has completed, which shows that vulnerability assessments have been successfully set up.
To start golden AMI vulnerability assessments:
 Sign in to the AWS Management Console and choose Lambda in the Services menu. Choose Functions. In the Functions pane, choose the StartContinuousAssessment function.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>